epc.eu 2018-10-09

# PRIVACY POLICY

European Policy Centre
Privacy Policy
PRIVACY POLICY
Please read this policy carefully to understand how we collect, use and process your personal data. We explain in
detail how we protect your privacy, how you can check and adapt your data at any time, and how the strict
compliance with this policy is monitored.
Definitions
This Privacy Policy applies to the European Policy Centre website (epc.eu) and any other website operated by the
European Policy Centre.
Introduction
The European Policy Centre website, including all information and materials contained on them, are managed by
the European Policy Centre.
For any questions regarding this Privacy Policy please contact us using the details below.
The European Policy Centre is committed to ensuring the privacy of all its users. This Privacy Policy governs all pages
on the European Policy Centre website. It does not apply to pages hosted by other organisations, including the
website of related organisations or third-party sites. The European Policy Centre website may be linked to the
websites of such other parties, but those other sites may have their own privacy policies which apply to them.
Consent
By using any European Policy Centre website, you consent to the terms of this Privacy Policy. The European Policy
Centre may change the terms of this Privacy Policy from time to time, in which case you will be informed.
What type of information do we collect and store?
The type and amount of information we receive and store depends on how you use the European Policy Centre
website.
You can access most pages on the European Policy Centre website without telling us who you are and without
revealing any personal information. Our web servers collect anonymous logs during user visits to the European
Policy Centre Website which provide valuable information for improving it in the future. For more information,
please consult our use of cookies statement.
We do not collect personal information (such as your name, address, phone number or e-mail address) on the
European Policy Centre website unless you choose to provide it, for example, when you express an interest in
joining the European Policy Centre or subscribe to our newsletters. In such cases, we collect your contact details i.e.
your name, address, e-mail address, telephone number, mobile phone number, fax number etc.
If you apply for a job or volunteer at the European Policy Centre, we will collect information about you so that we
can process your application and assess your suitability for the role.
Whenever you use the publicly available Wi-Fi network of the European Policy Centre on our premises, we also
collect your data. Also, by using our website, social media, e-mail response, cookies, clicking data, navigation data
and other technologies, we can collect data about you.
                                                                                                          Drafted on 23 May 2018
                                                           1                                              Updated on 5 June 2018

European Policy Centre
Privacy Policy
How do we use information collected?
Your personal information will be kept confidential.
It will only be used in connection with the purposes for which it is submitted, or as otherwise explained on the
European Policy Centre website, or as necessary for us to comply with our legal and auditing obligations.
In order to provide a service you have requested, we process personal data, for example, personal information
submitted with an expression of interest in joining the European Policy Centre will be used to action your
expression of interest and provide you with information about the European Policy Centre. Furthermore, if you
subscribe to one or more newsletters, we will only use your details to send you these newsletters.
If you do not wish to receive newsletters or information about our activities and publications, you can at any time
and without motivation unsubscribe free of charge. Every newsletter also gives you the opportunity to unsubscribe.
You can also send us an e-mail or indicate this preference in your membership application form.
Where we are legally obliged to, we will also process personal data e.g. your VAT number for invoicing purposes.
Where necessary for reasons of transparency or for a legitimate purpose, we display information on our website,
for example, we publish the names of organisations or persons from whom we have received EUR 5000 or above.
We also use your personal data for statistical purposes and to improve our services and products.
With regard to professional suppliers or companies with whom we work, we also keep, other than the data
mentioned above, company data such as the VAT number or enterprise number, the contact details of the
individuals concerned (name, function, telephone …) as well as of the associates, partners in the business.
The data about the publicly available Wi-Fi network on our premises are kept with a view to the security of our
network and to solve potential problems.
We never pass on your contact details to third parties without your consent.
How long do we keep your information?
If you use this website to submit a membership form, order a publication, register for an event or make a donation,
we will only keep your data for the time needed to provide the service you have requested. The European Policy
Centre may also decide to use some data in an anonymised and aggregated form over a longer period in order to
evaluate and make adjustments to its own activities e.g. statistics on events attendance, the number of downloads
of our publications. This does not involve identification of individual persons.
We endeavour to keep your information accurate and up to date and we only keep it for as long as is reasonable
and necessary.
                                                                                                        Drafted on 23 May 2018
                                                            2                                           Updated on 5 June 2018

European Policy Centre
Privacy Policy
How secure is your information?
Your personal information is retained by the European Policy Centre and its service providers in a secure environment.
We take appropriate security measures and use the latest security technology to protect your information from
unauthorised access, use, loss or publication. These systems and measures are tested on a regular basis and updated if
necessary.
However, the transmission of information over the Internet is never completely secure, so while we do our best to
protect personal information, we cannot guarantee the security of information transmitted to the European Policy
Centre website.
Do we share your personal information?
At no point will the information you provide be sold to a third-party organisation or person. The European Policy
Centre considers your data to be confidential information.
Neither will we share your information with third parties unless we are required to disclose the information by law
or in the following circumstances:
a. Auditing by our funders
For auditing purposes, we store participation lists of our events and meetings for up to five years.
b. Hosting and processing
Occasionally we will appeal to an external processor. This means, among other things, that for certain tasks or
research we hand over data temporarily to third parties if we do not have the means ourselves. If we do this, we
will always ensure that your information is handled confidentially and in a safe manner. We also always draw up a
contract with these processors. This way the processor will never be allowed to use your data on their own initiative
and your data will have to be erased as soon as the processor has finished the assignment.
The European Policy Centre website are hosted by third party service providers and therefore any personal details
you submit through the European Policy Centre website may be processed by that third-party service provider. We
may also use other third parties to process your personal details, for example, such third parties may process your
personal information to action expressions of interest to join the European Policy Centre, process payments on our
behalf or process mailing information for users who have signed up to receive our email updates and publications.
All of these third-party services providers will process your personal information only on the European Policy
Centre's behalf and will be bound by strict confidentiality conditions.
c. Payment processing and fraud
Where submitted, your card details may be disclosed to banks or relevant financial institutions to arrange
payments. In the case of a suspected fraudulent transaction, your details may be further disclosed for the sole
purpose of performing further checks, for example, disclosure to a credit checking agency.
The disclosure of your personal information discussed above may involve transfer of that information outside of the
European Union. Countries outside of the European Union, such as the United States, may not have data privacy
laws as strong as those in force in the European Union.
d. Database management
Within the European Policy Centre, your information is only available to authorised people who need to have access
to it in relation to their job.
e. Event participants lists
When you attend an EPC event or workshop, your name and organisation will appear on the list of participants. This
list will be distributed at the meeting itself to all event attendees. If the event is co-organised with partner
organisations, we may share the event participants list with those third parties. Under no circumstances will we
pass on your e-mail address without your express permission.
Use of cookies
A cookie is a text-only piece of information that a website transfers to your computer's hard disk so that the
website can remember who you are. A cookie will normally contain the name of the Internet domain from which
the cookie has come, the "lifetime" of the cookie, and a value, usually a randomly generated unique number.
You can restrict or disable the use of cookies in the settings of your web browser. Please click on the following link
for more information: www.aboutcookies.org.
                                                                                                            Drafted on 23 May 2018
                                                               3                                             Updated on 5 June 2018

European Policy Centre
Privacy Policy
Please click through to our use of cookies statement for more detailed information on cookies and how the
European Policy Centre uses them.
How can you access your information, correct or delete it?
When you become a member, partner or service provider of the European Policy Centre or subscribe to one of its
newsletters, the European Policy Centre stores certain data. This is why you also have certain rights concerning
these data. You have rights of access to the personal information we hold about you, to amend that information or,
in some circumstances, to withdraw your consent to our processing of your information, under data privacy law.
You can access any of your personal information that is processed by the European Policy Centre, check the data
and delete or correct any data that is incorrect or incomplete.
To exercise this right, we ask you to send a request to the European Policy Centre stating clearly what you want to
know, correct or delete. This request needs to be signed and dated and contain a copy of the front of your identity
card. The European Policy Centre will execute your request as soon as possible and send you a message accordingly.
If you have any further questions or concerns about this policy, please contact:
European Policy Centre
Rue du Trône 14-16
B-1000 Brussels
BELGIUM
Or please e-mail us at: privacy@epc.eu
Should you consider that your data have been handled incorrectly, you can submit a complaint to or contact the
Privacy Commission in Belgium or in your country of residence.
                                                                                                        Drafted on 23 May 2018
                                                           4                                            Updated on 5 June 2018
